



## **Rasanpreet Singh**

Email: rasankhalsa@gmail.com

M: +918506053401

#### **Profile Summary:**

About 6.5 Years of professional IT experience in Linux System Administration with extensive experience in Red hat Linux, Centos, Ubuntu and Windows Server Administration. I enjoy learning new technologies to help make people, processes and infrastructure better. I am actively learning and working on cloud (AWS). AWS SysOps and Solutions Architect Certified, RHCSA, RHCE and CCNA training's.

### **Key Skills:**

Operating Systems : Amazon Linux, Redhat Linux, CentOS, Ubuntu and Windows Server.

Web & APP Servers : Apache, Nginx, Apache Tomcat, SmartFoxServer.

Databases : MySQL, MariaDB, Mongo, PostgreSQL, AWS RDS.

Cloud Platforms : AWS Certified, Microsoft Azure.

Virtualization : VMware/ESXi, XenCenter.

Automation Tools : Ansible, Jenkins, Git, SVN, Nagios XI, New Relic APM.

# **Working Experience:**

Nov 2018 to till date: -working as Sr. Linux Administrator at IDS Infotech Ltd. IT Park, Chandigarh

**IDS INFOTECH LTD** Established in 1989, IDS Infotech Ltd. (IDS), has been a preferred Business Process Management and Software Solution provider to Fortune 500 companies. A team of over 1,000 trained and skilled professionals, work round-the-clock to deliver quality solutions. Our portfolio includes end-to-end Software services with various delivery centers in North India and multiple front-end offices globally, including US, UK and the Netherlands

### Job Responsibilities:

- Responsible for upkeep client's production Linux environments on AWS and their data-center environments.
- Providing Linux support from configuration to deploying all In-house Projects within company own data-center.
- Experienced with AWS foundational services and designing cost effective solutions with moving to the cloud.
- Designing cloud-based solutions based on customer requirements using AWS & VMware.
- Hands-on experience using compute, networking, storage, and database AWS services
- Gathering and analyzing performance metrics for solutions in both dedicated servers and visualized environments
- Complete Git workflow for the deployments on dev, UAT and prod environments and automated

- deployments though Jenkins pipeline.
- Ansible installation and configuration.

# Nov 2017 to Nov 2018: - working as Sr. IT Administrator at Gaussian Networks Pvt. Ltd.

**Gaussian Networks Pvt. Ltd.** specializes in online games development and hosting, that aims to take online gaming to the next level. It offers online version of poker, rummy, chess, scrabble, golf, and pool through adda52.com and adda52rummy.com

## Job Responsibilities:

- Handles day to day activities like monitoring systems, make sure applications are working, installation of new servers/redeployment of new servers and hardening.
- Installation / maintenance and deploying web and application servers Apache, PHP, Tomcat, Nginx, Node.js.
- Maintaining and implementing VMware ESX (versions 5.x 6.x) with **vCenter**, **vSphere**.
- Setup database failover by **replication** in MySQL and MariaDB to ensure performance and High availability of databases.
- Complete Git workflow for the deployments on dev, test and prod environments and automated deployments though **Jenkins** pipeline.
- Ensure application health and performance with application monitoring, and infrastructure monitoring by **NagiosXI**.
- Working with Network firewalls.
- H/W issue management via ILO console

### Aug 2016- Oct 2017: - working as Senior System Engineer at Espire Infolabs Pvt. Ltd. Gurgaon.

Global Company Specializing in Customer Experience with Solutions for Digital Experience Management, Applications Management Services, Enterprise.

Client – Toyota finance Services Australia

#### Job Responsibilities:

- Handling Infra support of App and DB Red-Hat Linux Boxes
- Daily monitoring health checks and database performance.
- Perform OS patch management, updates, OS hardening, and audits to ensure system integrity.
- Providing all solutions by handling tickets and weekly client communication.
- Proper documentation providing analysis and RCA's.

### **In House Projects**

Providing Linux support from configuration to deploying within company own datacenter.

## May 2015- Aug 2016: - Working as Linux Admin at Zataksoftech Pvt. Ltd. Gurgaon.

**Zataksoftech** is an offshore web development company that offer a wide range of web. Designing, ecommerce, website development services to grow your business online.

# Job Responsibilities:

- Management and configurations Configuration of Website and its management in all kind of hosting environment including shared hosting, VPS hosting, Dedicated Server Hosting, Cloud Hosting etc.
- Responsible for Mysql backups their scheduling and restoration process
- Responsible for Migration of server applications from one server to another (Web

server, DB servers)

- Configured and installed cPanel/WHM, Plesk, webmin, virtualmin.
- Handling Web and Database administration
- Responsible for SSL certificates implementation and their migrations process
- Working Knowledge of Amazon EC2 AWS
- Understanding Shell and other server-side scripting.
- Monitoring CPU utilization and disk usage and process tracking, load alert, ssh login Alert, server down alert with Email notifications
- Managing Window base SVN version controlling system for developers.

## January 2014 to March 2015 in HCL Services Ltd Chandigarh.

A listed subsidiary of HCL Group, is India's Premier Distribution and IT Services and Solutions Company. It has presence in 170 cities and 505 points of presence reaching 4000 towns throughout India and operations in emerging markets including South Asia, Middle East & Africa. Its headquarter in Noida.

Project Name : E-courts Systems

Client Name : Punjab & Haryana High Court

Domain : MySql Database on Linux

Role : System Administrator
Place : Chandigarh, Punjab.

# **Educational Qualification:**

- **BTech** Program in Discipline of CSE by aggregate of **70** % marks from PTU in 2012.
- 10+2 Program in Discipline of Non-Medical by aggregate of 64 % from P.S.E.B in 2008.
- Metric by aggregate of **79** % from P.S.E.B in 2006.

## **Certifications and Training's:**

- AWS Certificated Solutions Architect.
- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator
- RHCSA, RHCE and CCNA training's.